BRIAN A. CLARK

191 W. Woodruff Ave Physics Research Building The Ohio State University

Phone: (614) 247-8268 Email: clark.2668@osu.edu

Website: u.osu.edu/clark.2668

OrcID / inSPIRE: 0000-0003-4089-2245 / Brian.A.Clark.1

RESEARCH PROFILE

Columbus, OH 43210 USA

Experimental astrophysics PhD candidate and National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellow, working with the Askaryan Radio Array (ARA). Interested in ultra-high energy neutrino astronomy, specifically the construction, simulation, and data analysis of radio-based Antarctic neutrino telescopes.

EDUCATION

Ph.D in Physics, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio USA 2014-2019 (Expected) Advisor: Prof. Amy Connolly

M.S. in Physics, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio USA 2014-2016

B.A. in Physics, Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, Missouri USA 2010-2014

Cum Laude, Advisor: Prof. Henric Krawczynski

AWARDS

National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship	2016-2019
APS Divison of Astrophysics Travel Award	2017
OSU Graduate Enrichment Fellowship	2014-2015
WUSTL Undergraudate Physics Research Fellow	Summer 2011

EXPERIENCE

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH USA

Ph.D. Student, Ultra-High Energy Neutrino Astrophysics

August 2014 - present

- Developed frequency and time-series analysis techniques to analyze radio emission from solar flares in the ARA prototype station; this is the first extraterrestrial emission observed by the array.
- Implemented filtering techniques to remove human-made noise from ARA data, and utilized them in a search for a diffuse flux of ultra-high energy neutrinos.
- Built and tested printed circuit boards for RF signal conditioning and power distribution, improving access to instrument dynamic range and operability in harsh environments.
- Lead and directed the mechanical and electrical systems integration of three new neutrino detecting stations, including the management of a six person team of junior students.
- Deployed to Antarctica for five weeks to lead the commissioning and calibration of five neutrino detecting stations; performed rapid on site assessment of instrument performance.

Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO USA
Undergraduate Research Associate, X-Ray Astrophysics

October 2012 - May 2014

- Participated in X-Calibur collaboration to detect x-rays in the upper atmosphere, including fabrication of CCDs in a cleanroon environment.
- Wrote Monte Carlo simulations to explore Stokes parameters in x-ray astronomy by using methods of Bayesian confidence intervals.

PUBLICATIONS

- 4. "Design and Performance of an Interferometric Trigger Array for Radio Detection of High-Energy Neutrinos"
 - P. Allison *et. al.* for the ARA Collaboration (incl. **B. A. Clark**) Submitted to Nuclear Instruments and Methods A (2018). [arXiv:1809.04573]
- 3. "Observation of Reconstructable Radio Emission Coincident with an X-Class Solar Flare in the Askaryan Radio Array Prototype Station."
 - P. Allison *et. al.* for the ARA Collaboration (incl. **B. A. Clark** as corresponding author) Submitted to Astroparticle Physics (2018). [arXiv:1807.03335]
- 2. "Measurement of the real dielectric permittivity ϵ_r of glacial ice." P. Allison *et. al.* for the ARA Collaboration (incl. **B. A. Clark**) Submitted to the Journal of Glaciology (2017). [arXiv:1712.03301]
- "Analyzing the Data from X-ray Polarimeters with Stokes Paramters."
 F. Kislat, B. Clark, M. Bielicke, H. Krawczynski.
 Astroparticle Physics Vol 68 Pg 45-51 (2015). [arXiv:1409.6214]

SCIENTIFIC TALKS

National & International Conferences

- 3. APS April Meeting, Columbus OH.

 Directional Reconstruction as a Means of Lowering Thresholds for Point-Source Searches in the Askaryan Radio Array.
- 2. TeV Particle Astrophysics, Columbus OH. 2017/08/11 The Askaryan Radio Array: Current Status and Future Plans.
- 1. APS April Meeting, Washington DC. 2017/01/31 Observation of Reconstructable Radio Waveforms from Solar Flares with Askaryan Radio Array.

Colloquia, Seminars, and Other Talks

- 7. Ohio Section of the APS Fall 2018 Meeting, Toledo OH. 2018/09/29

 Latest Results in the Search for Ultra-High Energy Neutrinos in the Askaryan Radio Array
- 6. OSU Physics Summer Seminar Series, Columbus OH. 2018/06/26

 Ultra-High Energy Neutrino Astrophysics with Radio-Based Detectors.
- 5. OSU CCAPP Seminar, Columbus OH.

 The Askaryan Radio Array: Detector Status and Prospects for Using Directional Reconstruction in Point-Source Searches.
- 4. Colloquium, College of Wooster Physics Department, Wooster OH. 2016/10/04 Ultra-High Energy Neutrino Astrophysics with Radio Detectors.
- 3. Computing in High Energy Astropart. Phys. Research 2016, Columbus OH. 2016/05/26

 Machine Learning Prospects in Trigger Thresholds for High Energy Radio Neutrino Astronomy.
- 2. OSU Physics Summer Seminar Series, Columbus OH. 2016/04/23 Trigger Thresholds in High Energy Neutrino Astronomy.
- 1. Ohio Section of the APS Spring 2016 Meeting, Dayton OH. 2016/04/09 Ultra-High Energy Neutrino Astrophysics with the Askaryan Radio Array (ARA).

RELEVANT SKILLS

Programming/Software	C++, C, Python, BASH, Energia, Code Composer Studio, PADS
Mechanical/Electrical	Surface mount soldering, power distribution, RF signal conditioning

TEACHING

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH

TA Training Facilitator, University Center for the Advancement Teaching

August 2016

- Facilitated two-day "introduction to teaching and learning" workshop for 30 first-time Teaching Assitants across the Universities 40 STEM science programs.
- Built confidence in new TAs, guided development of teaching identities, adressed diversity in the classroom, and aided participant planning for longterm classroom success.

Teaching Assistant—"Astronomy 1143: Stars, Galaxies, and Cosmology"

Spring 2016

- Taught 80 student introductory survey course, open to students across the university.
- Aided student learning by teaching review sessions and lecturing when lead faculty was absent.
- Moderated online forum, in collaboration with lead faculty, for students to exchange questions and clarify concepts.

Teaching Assistant-"Physics 1251: E&M, Optics, and Quantum Mechanics"

Fall 2015

- Guided student learning in the recitation and laboratory context for four contact hours per week.
- Facilitated quantitative laboratory experiments including team-based problem solving exercises.
- Designed rubrics for fair, efficient, and consistent grading of quiz and examination instruments.

OUTREACH AND SERVCE

Coordinator for ASPIRE Workshop for High School Girls, OSU	July 2015-present
Physics Climate and Diversity Committee, OSU	January 2017-May 2018
Volunteer Judge, Ohio State Science Day	2015-present
Talk, Columbus Science Pub	May 2018
Talk, The Wellington School, Columbus, OH	April 2018
Officer, Physics Graduate Student Council, OSU	October 2014-May 2017

MENTORSHIP

Graduate Students: Lauren Ennesser, Keith McBride, Andrés Medina, Julie Rolla,

Jorge Torres-Espinosa

Undergraduate Students: Ian Best, Suren Gourapura, Hannah Hassan, Spoorthi Nagasmudram,

Victoria Niu, Jude Rajasekera, Lucas Smith, Jason Torok

High School Students: Addison Hartman, Natalie Keyes

REFERENCES

Amy Connolly

Associate Professor of Physics The Ohio State University connolly@physics.osu.edu 614-292-4368

James Beatty

Professor of Physics and Astronomy The Ohio State University beatty@mps.ohio-state.edu 614-247-8413

Dave Besson

Professor of Physics and Astronomy The University of Kansas zedlam@ku.edu 785-864-4741